{
  "quiz": {
    "questionItem": [
      {
        "question": "How do you join strings together in PHP?",
        "panswer": [
          "$var1 = 'a' + 'b';",
          "$var1 = 'a'.'b';",
          "$var1 = 'a' JOIN 'b';",
          "$var1 = 'a'++'b';"
        ],
        "aanswer": "$var1 = 'a'.'b';"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is NOT a valid assignement operator?",
        "panswer": [
          "$a -= $a;",
          "$a <= $a;",
          "$a *= $a;",
          "$a += $a;"
        ],
        "aanswer": "$a <= $a;"
      },
      {
        "question": "What is the difference between 'include' and 'require'?",
        "panswer": [
          "Include only includes the HTML in the file, while require includes the PHP code too.",
          "Require only includes the HTML in the file, while include imports the HTML and PHP code.",
          "Require will stop executing as soon as an error is reached, and include will continue executing the code after the error.",
          "Include will stop executing as soon as an error is reached, and require will continue executing the code after the error."
        ],
        "aanswer": "Require will stop executing as soon as an error is reached, and include will continue executing the code after the error."
      },
      {
        "question": "What keyword(s) can you use to add an alternative condition to an if statement that executes different code?",
        "panswer": [
          "else if",
          "and if",
          "elif",
          "or if"
        ],
        "aanswer": "else if"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of these is not a valid statement?",
        "panswer": [
          "if($a === '7') { }",
          "if($a != 8) { }",
          "if($a NEQ 8) { }",
          "if(!$a) { }"
        ],
        "aanswer": "if($a NEQ 8) { }"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is the correct way to start a function?",
        "panswer": [
          "function testFunc()",
          "function testFunc{}",
          "function testFunc[]",
          "def testFunc{}"
        ],
        "aanswer": "function testFunc()"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following keywords is used to start a conditional in a PHP switch statement?",
        "panswer": [
          "case",
          "if",
          "cond",
          "condition"
        ],
        "aanswer": "case"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is a valid way to start a for loop in PHP that would print out the numbers 0 through 4?",
        "panswer": [
          "for($i < 5; $i = 0;)",
          "for($i = 0; $i < 5; $i++)",
          "for($i < 5;)",
          "for( $i < 5; $i = 0; $i++)"
        ],
        "aanswer": "for($i = 0; $i < 5; $i++)"
      },
      {
        "question": "How do you create an array?",
        "panswer": [
          "$myArray = new array();",
          "$myArray = Array.create();",
          "$myArray = array();",
          "$myArray = create(array);"
        ],
        "aanswer": "$myArray = array();"
      },
      {
        "question": "What keyword can you use to exit out of a loop and continue onto the next code after the loop?",
        "panswer": [
          "exit();",
          "continue",
          "break",
          "skip"
        ],
        "aanswer": "break"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following variables can NOT be used to obtain the form data after a form is submitted?",
        "panswer": [
          "$_FORMDATA",
          "$_REQUEST",
          "$_GET",
          "$_POST"
        ],
        "aanswer": "$_FORMDATA"
      },
      {
        "question": "What function can you use to get the position of a string or character inside a string?",
        "panswer": [
          "string_position",
          "strrpos",
          "len",
          "length"
        ],
        "aanswer": "strrpos"
      },
      {
        "question": "What function can you use to break a string with a sentence into an array of words?",
        "panswer": [
          "splice",
          "array_split",
          "break",
          "explode"
        ],
        "aanswer": "explode"
      },
      {
        "question": "How would you open a file to read from it in PHP?",
        "panswer": [
          "$myFile = fopen('r', 'sampleFile.txt');",
          "$myFile = fopen('sampleFile.txt', 'r');",
          "$myFile = open('sampleFile.txt', 'r');",
          "$myFile = open('r', 'sampleFile.txt');"
        ],
        "aanswer": "$myFile = fopen('sampleFile.txt', 'r');"
      },
      {
        "question": "How would you read the first 20 characters of a file if the variable $a contains the link to the file?",
        "panswer": [
          "$myFileContents = fread($a, 20);",
          "$myFileContents = fread(20,$a);",
          "$myFileContents = read(20,$a);",
          "$myFileContents = read($a, 20);"
        ],
        "aanswer": "$myFileContents = fread($a, 20);"
      },
      {
        "question": "How do you write contents to a file?",
        "panswer": [
          "output ('some content');",
          "echo ('some content');",
          "write('some content');",
          "fwrite('some content');"
        ],
        "aanswer": "fwrite('some content');"
      },
      {
        "question": "What function do you use to delete a file in PHP?",
        "panswer": [
          "delete()",
          "fdelete()",
          "unlink()",
          "remove()"
        ],
        "aanswer": "unlink()"
      },
      {
        "question": "What function can you use to transfer an uploaded file to a new location?",
        "panswer": [
          "transfer()",
          "move_uploaded_file()",
          "move_file()",
          "transfer_file()"
        ],
        "aanswer": "move_uploaded_file()"
      },
      {
        "question": "PHP is an acronym for:",
        "panswer": [
          "Pre Hypertext Processor",
          "Post Hypertext Processor",
          "PHP Hypertext Preprocessor",
          "Post Hypertext Preprocessor"
        ],
        "aanswer": "PHP Hypertext Preprocessor"
      },
      {
        "question": "What type of language is PHP?",
        "panswer": [
          "Client side",
          "Server side",
          "Windows side",
          "Controller side"
        ],
        "aanswer": "Server side"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is a valid PHP script tag:",
        "panswer": [
          "<PHP PHP>",
          "<?php php?>",
          "<php></php>",
          "<?php ?>"
        ],
        "aanswer": "<?php ?>"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following does NOT provide an output to the screen?",
        "panswer": [
          "to_screen",
          "echo",
          "print_r",
          "print"
        ],
        "aanswer": "to_screen"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a valid variable name in PHP?",
        "panswer": [
          "$camelCase",
          "$B_Y_E",
          "$2cat",
          "$something"
        ],
        "aanswer": "$2cat"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which of the following is NOT a PHP variable scope:",
        "panswer": [
          "local",
          "global",
          "static",
          "defined"
        ],
        "aanswer": "defined"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which is NOT true about integers in PHP?",
        "panswer": [
          "An integer must have at least one digit (0-9)",
          "An integer can contain comma or blanks",
          "An integer must not have a decimal point",
          "An integer can be either positive or negative"
        ],
        "aanswer": "An integer can contain comma or blanks"
      },
      {
        "question": "The strlen() function in PHP:",
        "panswer": [
          "returns the length of a string, in characters",
          "searchs for a specified character or text within a string",
          "returns the number of words in a string",
          "randomizes order of letters in a string"
        ],
        "aanswer": "returns the length of a string, in characters"
      },
      {
        "question": "The strpos() function in PHP:",
        "panswer": [
          "returns the length of a string, in characters",
          "returns the number of words in a string",
          "randomizes order of letters in a string",
          "searchs for a specified character or text within a string"
        ],
        "aanswer": "searchs for a specified character or text within a string"
      },
      {
        "question": "What function would you use to determine if a variable is empty?",
        "panswer": [
          "is_null",
          "check_value",
          "empty",
          "isset"
        ],
        "aanswer": "empty"
      },
      {
        "question": "What function counts the lenght of an array?",
        "panswer": [
          "count",
          "arr_sum",
          "length",
          "arr_length"
        ],
        "aanswer": "count"
      },
      {
        "question": "What would the following statement output to the screen: var str = \"Hello world!\"; var res = str.substr(1,4);",
        "panswer": [
          "hello",
          "rld!",
          "o wor",
          "ello"
        ],
        "aanswer": "ello"
      },
      {
        "question": "What function converts a string to all lowercase?",
        "panswer": [
          "stringToLower",
          "lowercase",
          "lower",
          "strtolower"
        ],
        "aanswer": "strtolower"
      },
      {
        "question": "What function prints human-readable information about a variable?",
        "panswer": [
          "echo_r",
          "print_r",
          "arr_print",
          "print_hr"
        ],
        "aanswer": "print_r"
      },
      {
        "question": "What would this output: echo(floor(-5.1)",
        "panswer": [
          "6",
          "-6",
          "-5",
          "5"
        ],
        "aanswer": "-6"
      },
      {
        "question": "What does the 'key' function do?",
        "panswer": [
          "Computes the difference of arrays using keys for comparison",
          "Pushes one or more elements onto the end of an array",
          "Fetches the key of an array",
          "Filters elements of an array using a callback function"
        ],
        "aanswer": "Fetches the key of an array"
      },
      {
        "question": "What function would rearrange an array backwards?",
        "panswer": [
          "array_backward",
          "array_reverse",
          "array_rekey",
          "array_diff"
        ],
        "aanswer": "array_reverse"
      },
      {
        "question": "Which function is used to return true if a given value exists in an array (and false if it doesn't)?",
        "panswer": [
          "array_key_exists",
          "has_value",
          "array_value_exists",
          "in_array"
        ],
        "aanswer": "has_value"
      }
    ]
  }
}